<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calling It Round</title>
    <link>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Calling It Round</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic Terminology</title>
      <link>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/basic_terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/basic_terminology/</guid>
      <description>Basic Terminology #  English change ringing has a rich history spanning hundreds of years; it’s little wonder we’ve managed to create a language all our own. Calling It Round assumes you have a certain amount of knowledge about change ringing terminology already. For example, by this time in your ringing development, you will be familiar with quite a lot of ringing terminology. “Look to” makes your ears perk up, you might have a favorite “method,” and you might already have rung a “quarter peal” (and if you haven’t already &amp;ndash; you know what it is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Your Voice</title>
      <link>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/finding_your_voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/finding_your_voice/</guid>
      <description>Finding your voice: Putting the calls in #  Now that you’ve got some terminology floating around your head, it’s time to start building up skills to help you learn to call your first touch. Let’s put your knowledge to practical use and think about where and how to put the bobs in.
By the end of this submodule, you should be able to:
 Explain where, in a lead, the calls should go in; Listen to and “troubleshoot” a video of a caller who might have put some calls in the wrong places  In addition, you will be given some exercises to try out in your tower or with your handbell band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short Touch</title>
      <link>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/a_short_touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/a_short_touch/</guid>
      <description>A short touch of… : Some simple touches for practice #  In this section, we’ll be covering some short and simple touches you can use for practice. This section will focus on touches that are short enough that it is practical to discuss which call is made at each lead, leaving discussions of “calling positions” (such as In, Wrong, or Make) for a later submodule.
Terminology #  Here we’ll be learning about calling using very simple compositions which are limited to a single method and a small number of calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying &#34;In, Out, Make&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/demystifying_wrong_home_wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/demystifying_wrong_home_wrong/</guid>
      <description>Demystifying “In, Out, Make”: The most common calling positions #  In this section, we’ll start to build the vocabulary and skills you’ll need to call longer and more complicated touches. When touches are longer than a few leads, it quickly becomes tiresome to memorize a long series of “plain, bob, bob, plain, bob, plain…”. To fix that problem, callers and conductors often use calling positions to help them remember where to put in the calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Learning Short Touches</title>
      <link>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/reading_and_learning_compositions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/reading_and_learning_compositions/</guid>
      <description>Reading and learning short touches using the most common calling positions #  In this section, we’ll put together everything we’ve covered over the course of Caling It Round by learning 2 different short touches that use the most common calling positions. In addition, I’ve compiled some collections of other short touches that use these calling positions as well; these collections will be included at the bottom as resources.
Wrong Home, Wrong Home #   The first touch we’ll go over is a great one for practice night; simple, with relatively few calls, and short enough for a second attempt if the first goes awry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handbell-Specific Guidance</title>
      <link>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/handbell_guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebook.brynmarie.com/docs/calling/handbell_guidance/</guid>
      <description>Handbell-specific guidance #  Much of the information in Calling It Round applies equally well to tower bell ringers and handbell ringers. However, there are some special tricks that are mostly suitable for handbell ringers that I think will be useful for you as you make a start at calling. Some of these tips may not be useful right away, and this will likely vary ringer to ringer; so take what&amp;rsquo;s useful and leave the rest!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
