<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calling It Round</title>
    <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Calling It Round</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Your Touch</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/1_choosing_your_touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/1_choosing_your_touch/</guid>
      <description>Choosing Your Touch #  Regardless of whether you are newly learning to call and conduct or whether you&amp;rsquo;ve already called 1000 peals of Surprise Royal, there will be times when you need to pick a touch for a practice night, or pick a quarter peal or peal composition. If you&amp;rsquo;re very experienced, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely already got a &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; for which compositions you prefer in style, but if you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out, it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual to feel a bit adrift in the huge variety of compositions available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placing Your Band</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/2_placing_your_band/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/2_placing_your_band/</guid>
      <description>Placing Your Band #  Band placement is, I think, one of the trickier things that callers and conductors do (other than calling or conducting!). Not everyone chooses to place bands, for a variety of reasons, but many callers and conductors do choose to, especially for quarter peal and peal attempts.
However, in my experience it&amp;rsquo;s rare that there is frank discussion of how exactly bands are placed. I think that a lot of this reluctance of discussion is due to the fact that it can be fairly socially tricky to place a band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Guidance</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/3_giving_guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/3_giving_guidance/</guid>
      <description>Giving Guidance #  There are many opportunities for a caller or conductor to give guidance. These may be as simple as a short reminder about the composition before beginning a touch, or may be as complex as giving instructions about the coursing orders during a peal attempt. Here are some thoughts about the different times and manners in which callers and conductors give guidance.
Before the ringing #  Everyone has a different philosophy about how much guidance to give before a touch, or a quarter peal or peal attempt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Practice</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/4_getting_practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/4_getting_practice/</guid>
      <description>Getting Practice #  A lot of this chapter on Supplemental Skills has been devoted to the growth and development of the band through the actions of the caller or conductor; that is, watching out for getting the right type of touch, placing your band just so, and giving guidance in a kind and sensitive manner while also being effective.
This section, on &amp;ldquo;Getting Practice,&amp;rdquo; is about how to effectively advocate for yourself in getting the sorts of practice you will need to become a good conductor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conducting in Hand</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/5_conducting_in_hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/5_conducting_in_hand/</guid>
      <description>Conducting in Hand #  Much of the information in Calling It Round applies equally well to tower bell ringers and handbell ringers. However, there are some special tricks that are mostly suitable for handbell ringers that I think will be useful for you as you make a start at calling and conducting. Some of these tips may not be useful right away, and this will likely vary ringer to ringer; so take what&amp;rsquo;s useful and leave the rest!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
