<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calling It Round</title>
    <link>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Calling It Round</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Checking the Ringing</title>
      <link>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/1_checking_the_ringing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/1_checking_the_ringing/</guid>
      <description>Checking the Ringing #  The ability to check the ringing is often thought to be the key difference between a caller and a conductor. In this chapter on Conducting, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about tracking and checking the ringing, using information that you can get from the composition itself and doing some study beforehand.
This first section is on checking the ringing, and it focuses on how to use memorization and other skills you already have to check the ringing, without the use of coursing orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursing Orders</title>
      <link>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/2_coursing_orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/2_coursing_orders/</guid>
      <description>Coursing Orders #  Coursing orders are a fundamental tool of the conductor, and many if not most conductors use them for checking the ringing. But what is a coursing order? This section is here to answer that question. For this section and the next, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on coursing orders in the context of Plain Bob.
Back to Basics: Plain Hunt #  Let&amp;rsquo;s take a good look at plain hunting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transposing Coursing Orders</title>
      <link>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/3_transposing_coursing_orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/3_transposing_coursing_orders/</guid>
      <description>Transposing Coursing Orders #  You might&amp;rsquo;ve felt a bit suspicious in the last section about my proposed use for coursing orders in conducting. I suggested that if you know the coursing order, you can watch how you pass the bells around you and thereby set people straight if you are passing them in an order that is not the correct coursing order.
In the plain course, knowing the coursing order is as easy as memorizing a short string of numbers, often in a very pleasing order (with such helpful mnemonics as &amp;ldquo;up the odds, down the evens!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round The Circle</title>
      <link>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/4_round_the_circle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/4_round_the_circle/</guid>
      <description>Round The Circle #  In many resources about conducting, a particular emphasis is put on learning how to conduct from the tenor. This emphasis arises from a combination of long-held tradition and compositional convenience, but conducting from the tenor is not your only choice! This section of Calling It Round will spotlight different places in the circle from which it is possible to conduct.
Conducting from: the observation bell #  In many compositions, the observation bell is the heaviest working bell, and all of the calling positions are portrayed relative to its path through the blueline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing It Round</title>
      <link>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/5_bringing_it_round/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/5_bringing_it_round/</guid>
      <description>Bringing It Round #  We&amp;rsquo;ve been through a lot of material together! This last section is just for compositions to get you good practice at &amp;ldquo;bringing it round,&amp;rdquo; so to speak.
Composition collections #  The skills and techniques you&amp;rsquo;ve learned can be applied to nearly any composition, including those from the chapter on Calling. However, it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes useful to have access to a small list of compositions to choose from which are uniquely suited to one&amp;rsquo;s needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
