<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calling It Round</title>
    <link>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Calling It Round</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finding Your Voice</title>
      <link>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/1_finding_your_voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/1_finding_your_voice/</guid>
      <description>Finding Your Voice #  Welcome to Calling It Round! In this chapter on Calling, we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering the basics required to call one’s first touch, and to learn simple compositions independently. Calling It Round assumes you have a certain amount of knowledge about change ringing terminology already. “Look to” makes your ears perk up, you might have a favorite “method,” and you might already have rung a “quarter peal” (and if you haven’t already&amp;mdash;you know what it is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Touches</title>
      <link>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/2_simple_touches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/2_simple_touches/</guid>
      <description>Simple Touches #  In this section, we’ll be covering some short and simple touches you can use for practice. This section will focus on touches that are short enough that it is practical to discuss which call is made at each lead, leaving discussions of “calling positions” (such as In, Wrong, or Make) for a later submodule. Examples are focused on various stages of Plain Bob as well as a few other common methods, with a few short touches of Grandsire included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying &#34;In, Out, Make&#34;</title>
      <link>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/3_demystifying_in_out_make/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/3_demystifying_in_out_make/</guid>
      <description>Demystifying “In, Out, Make”: The most common calling positions #  In this section, we’ll start to build the vocabulary and skills you’ll need to call longer and more complicated touches. When touches are longer than a few leads, it quickly becomes tiresome to memorize a long series of “plain, bob, bob, plain, bob, plain…”. To fix that problem, callers and conductors often use calling positions to help them remember where to put in the calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Short Touches</title>
      <link>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/4_learning_short_touches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/4_learning_short_touches/</guid>
      <description>Learning Short Touches #  In this section, we’ll put together everything we’ve covered over the course of Calling It Round so far by learning 2 different short touches that use the most common calling positions. In addition, I’ve compiled some collections of other short touches that use these calling positions as well; these collections will be included at the bottom as resources.
Wrong Home, Wrong Home #    The first touch we’ll go over is a great one for practice night; simple, with relatively few calls, and short enough for a second attempt if the first goes awry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less Common Calling Positions</title>
      <link>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/5_less_common_calling_positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/5_less_common_calling_positions/</guid>
      <description>Less Common Calling Positions #  As we discussed in the previous section, you can do a lot with a little; knowing only a few calling positions can enable you to call a good number of touches. However, to unlock the rest of the huge treasure trove of compositions that exist, it’s necessary to know just a few more things. In this section, we’ll cover:
 A few more common calling positions (enough to get you through a majority of commonly-called compositions) A common touch, used for practices or Sunday services, that uses some of these new calling positions as well as some familiar ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Quarter-Length Compositions (or Longer)</title>
      <link>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/6_learning_quarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cccbr.github.io/callingitround/docs/calling/6_learning_quarter/</guid>
      <description>Learning Quarter-Length Compositions (or Longer) #  In this concluding section of the chapter on Calling, we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering learning quarter-length or longer compositions. I debated for a long time whether to put this section in the Calling chapter or the Conducting chapter, because once you are calling longer compositions it is frequently very helpful to begin checking the ringing (conducting); however, it isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary and I know I certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t checking the ringing when I called my first quarter peal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
