<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calling It Round</title>
    <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Calling It Round</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Checking the Ringing</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/1_checking_the_ringing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/1_checking_the_ringing/</guid>
      <description>Checking the Ringing #  The ability to check the ringing is often thought to be the key difference between a caller and a conductor. In this chapter on Conducting, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about tracking and checking the ringing, using information that you can get from the composition itself and doing some study beforehand.
This first section is on checking the ringing, and it focuses on how to use memorization and other skills you already have to check the ringing, without the use of coursing orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Your Touch</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/1_choosing_your_touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/1_choosing_your_touch/</guid>
      <description>Choosing Your Touch #  Regardless of whether you are newly learning to call and conduct or whether you&amp;rsquo;ve already called 1000 peals of Surprise Royal, there will be times when you need to pick a touch for a practice night, or pick a quarter peal or peal composition. If you&amp;rsquo;re very experienced, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely already got a &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; for which compositions you prefer in style, but if you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out, it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual to feel a bit adrift in the huge variety of compositions available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursing Orders</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/2_coursing_orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/2_coursing_orders/</guid>
      <description>Coursing Orders #  Coursing orders are a fundamental tool of the conductor, and many if not most conductors use them for checking the ringing. But what is a coursing order? This section is here to answer that question. For this section and the next, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on coursing orders in the context of Plain Bob.
Back to Basics: Plain Hunt #  Let&amp;rsquo;s take a good look at plain hunting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Your Voice</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/1_finding_your_voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/1_finding_your_voice/</guid>
      <description>Finding Your Voice #  Welcome to Calling It Round! In this chapter on Calling, we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering the basics required to call one’s first touch, and to learn simple compositions independently. Calling It Round assumes you have a certain amount of knowledge about change ringing terminology already. “Look to” makes your ears perk up, you might have a favorite “method,” and you might already have rung a “quarter peal” (and if you haven’t already&amp;mdash;you know what it is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placing Your Band</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/2_placing_your_band/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/2_placing_your_band/</guid>
      <description>Placing Your Band #  Band placement is, I think, one of the trickier things that callers and conductors do (other than calling or conducting!). Not everyone chooses to place bands, for a variety of reasons, but many callers and conductors do choose to, especially for quarter peal and peal attempts.
However, in my experience it&amp;rsquo;s rare that there is frank discussion of how exactly bands are placed. I think that a lot of this reluctance of discussion is due to the fact that it can be fairly socially tricky to place a band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Guidance</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/3_giving_guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/3_giving_guidance/</guid>
      <description>Giving Guidance #  There are many opportunities for a caller or conductor to give guidance. These may be as simple as a short reminder about the composition before beginning a touch, or may be as complex as giving instructions about the coursing orders during a peal attempt. Here are some thoughts about the different times and manners in which callers and conductors give guidance.
Before the ringing #  Everyone has a different philosophy about how much guidance to give before a touch, or a quarter peal or peal attempt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Touches</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/2_simple_touches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/2_simple_touches/</guid>
      <description>Simple Touches #  In this section, we’ll be covering some short and simple touches you can use for practice. This section will focus on touches that are short enough that it is practical to discuss which call is made at each lead, leaving discussions of “calling positions” (such as In, Wrong, or Make) for a later submodule. Examples are focused on various stages of Plain Bob as well as a few other common methods, with a few short touches of Grandsire included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transposing Coursing Orders</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/3_transposing_coursing_orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/3_transposing_coursing_orders/</guid>
      <description>Transposing Coursing Orders #  You might&amp;rsquo;ve felt a bit suspicious in the last section about my proposed use for coursing orders in conducting. I suggested that if you know the coursing order, you can watch how you pass the bells around you and thereby set people straight if you are passing them in an order that is not the correct coursing order.
In the plain course, knowing the coursing order is as easy as memorizing a short string of numbers, often in a very pleasing order (with such helpful mnemonics as &amp;ldquo;up the odds, down the evens!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying &#34;In, Out, Make&#34;</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/3_demystifying_in_out_make/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/3_demystifying_in_out_make/</guid>
      <description>Demystifying “In, Out, Make”: The most common calling positions #  In this section, we’ll start to build the vocabulary and skills you’ll need to call longer and more complicated touches. When touches are longer than a few leads, it quickly becomes tiresome to memorize a long series of “plain, bob, bob, plain, bob, plain…”. To fix that problem, callers and conductors often use calling positions to help them remember where to put in the calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Practice</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/4_getting_practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/4_getting_practice/</guid>
      <description>Getting Practice #  A lot of this chapter on Supplemental Skills has been devoted to the growth and development of the band through the actions of the caller or conductor; that is, watching out for getting the right type of touch, placing your band just so, and giving guidance in a kind and sensitive manner while also being effective.
This section, on &amp;ldquo;Getting Practice,&amp;rdquo; is about how to effectively advocate for yourself in getting the sorts of practice you will need to become a good conductor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round The Circle</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/4_round_the_circle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/4_round_the_circle/</guid>
      <description>Round The Circle #  In many resources about conducting, a particular emphasis is put on learning how to conduct from the tenor. This emphasis arises from a combination of long-held tradition and compositional convenience, but conducting from the tenor is not your only choice! This section of Calling It Round will spotlight different places in the circle from which it is possible to conduct.
Conducting from: the observation bell #  In many compositions, the observation bell is the heaviest working bell, and all of the calling positions are portrayed relative to its path through the blueline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing It Round</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/5_bringing_it_round/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/conducting/5_bringing_it_round/</guid>
      <description>Bringing It Round #  We&amp;rsquo;ve been through a lot of material together! This last section is just for compositions to get you good practice at &amp;ldquo;bringing it round,&amp;rdquo; so to speak.
Composition collections #  The skills and techniques you&amp;rsquo;ve learned can be applied to nearly any composition, including those from the chapter on Calling. However, it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes useful to have access to a small list of compositions to choose from which are uniquely suited to one&amp;rsquo;s needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conducting in Hand</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/5_conducting_in_hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/supplemental_skills/5_conducting_in_hand/</guid>
      <description>Conducting in Hand #  Much of the information in Calling It Round applies equally well to tower bell ringers and handbell ringers. However, there are some special tricks that are mostly suitable for handbell ringers that I think will be useful for you as you make a start at calling and conducting. Some of these tips may not be useful right away, and this will likely vary ringer to ringer; so take what&amp;rsquo;s useful and leave the rest!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Short Touches</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/4_learning_short_touches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/4_learning_short_touches/</guid>
      <description>Learning Short Touches #  In this section, we’ll put together everything we’ve covered over the course of Calling It Round so far by learning 2 different short touches that use the most common calling positions. In addition, I’ve compiled some collections of other short touches that use these calling positions as well; these collections will be included at the bottom as resources.
Wrong Home, Wrong Home #    The first touch we’ll go over is a great one for practice night; simple, with relatively few calls, and short enough for a second attempt if the first goes awry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less Common Calling Positions</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/5_less_common_calling_positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/5_less_common_calling_positions/</guid>
      <description>Less Common Calling Positions #  As we discussed in the previous section, you can do a lot with a little; knowing only a few calling positions can enable you to call a good number of touches. However, to unlock the rest of the huge treasure trove of compositions that exist, it’s necessary to know just a few more things. In this section, we’ll cover:
 A few more common calling positions (enough to get you through a majority of commonly-called compositions) A common touch, used for practices or Sunday services, that uses some of these new calling positions as well as some familiar ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Quarter-Length Compositions (or Longer)</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/6_learning_quarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/calling/6_learning_quarter/</guid>
      <description>Learning Quarter-Length Compositions (or Longer) #  In this concluding section of the chapter on Calling, we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering learning quarter-length or longer compositions. I debated for a long time whether to put this section in the Calling chapter or the Conducting chapter, because once you are calling longer compositions it is frequently very helpful to begin checking the ringing (conducting); however, it isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary and I know I certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t checking the ringing when I called my first quarter peal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acknowledgements</title>
      <link>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/acknowledgements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brynmarier.github.io/ebook-site/docs/acknowledgements/</guid>
      <description>Final Words #  I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say that there is a lot more content about calling and conducting than I could possibly write for Calling It Round. One of the biggest joys of ringing, for me, is the possibility of constant growth and learning; and there&amp;rsquo;s so much more to learn about conducting than the meagre amount I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to set down here. My hope is that this site was helpful in giving you grounding in some basics, giving you context for some common conventions, and giving you a reason to go practice!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
